# **Robert Grayson**

Puratorie 302 Todoroki 5-1-14 Setagaya-ku Tokyo-to 158-0082 Japan +88 80 2237 4372 robert.samuel.grayson@gmail.com

LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/rob-grayson

**Personal site**: <a href="https://findrob.netlify.app">https://findrob.netlify.app</a> **GitHub**: <a href="https://github.com/hummus-erectus">https://github.com/hummus-erectus</a>

#### Overview

Self-taught front-end developer with a background in linguistics. Possessing nine years' experience in planning and implementing onsite and online learning material, and a desire to leverage strengths in communication and problem solving toward exciting projects.

# Work Experience

## J Prep Liberal Arts

Tokyo, Japan

Instructor (part-time)

April 2022 – present

- Continuing to teach high-level classes to students wishing to enter top universities abroad and in Japan
- Focusing on self-development with the additional time this position provides

#### Chief of TOEFL Curriculum

March 2018 - present

- Produced curricula for ESL students at advanced levels, including test-specific courses and general academic skills courses, to stringent deadlines
- Adapted existing courses for online instruction and evaluation
- Managed web-based learning environment (Moodle), created resources for teachers and students including quizzes and revision tools
- Oversaw teaching and online grading of written assignments by native and non-native English teachers
- Worked with a team of engineers, content creators and illustrators to build a vocabulary app for IOS

### Head Instructor

May 2015 - March 2018

- Created and implemented Writing for Academic Purposes curriculum, incorporating style guides such as MLA and Chicago
- Designed workshops for teachers based on instituting theories from applied linguistics in the classroom

Instructor (part-time)

Nov 2013 - May 2015

- Facilitated discussions between junior- and high-school students on academic topics and current affairs
- Graded students' essays and prepared speeches

#### **ACE Pronunciation School**

Tokyo, Japan

Instructor and Curriculum Coordinator (part time)

June 2013 - May 2015

- Authored comprehensive grammar curriculum for adults
- Contributed to published English pronunciation textbooks
- Produced content for company social media
- Tutored adult learners of English (largely doctors, executives and other professionals)

#### RIKEN Brain Science Institute

Saitama, Japan

Research Assistant

Sept 2012 - Nov 2013

- Conducted linguistic experiments with infants
- Edited videos of experiments and analyzed data
- Presented research to peers and the public through 'open day' events

## Kuju Entertainment Ltd.

London/Brighton, UK

**QA** Assistant

June 2006 - December 2006

- Provided quality assurance for video games produced for publishers such as Sony, Nintendo and Sega
- Used database and workflow software to catalog bugs and collaborate with developers
- Communicated with international staff, particularly Japanese representatives from publishing companies

# Volunteering Tokyo Vegan Meetup

Experience

Co-organizer

2016 - present

- Organize and promote events through social media
- Participate in panels about veganism, SDGs, and related topics at universities
- Curate YouTube channel
- Communicate with restaurants and festival organizers to

Robert Grayson

Puratorie 302 Todoroki 5-1-14 Setagaya-ku Tokyo-to 158-0082 Japan +88 80
2237 4372 robert.samuel.grayson@gmail.com
LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/rob-grayson
Personal site: https://findrob.netlify.app
GitHub: https://github.com/hummus-erectus

host events

 Welcome attendees and provide information https://www.meetup.com/vegan-389/

### **Education** Coursera

Meta Front-End Developer

Aug 2022 – Present

**Professional Certificate** 

In-depth courses in HTML/ CSS, JavaScript, (Advanced)
 React, version control, UI/ UX design

## **University of Amsterdam**

MSc Brain and Cognitive Sciences (First Year)

Oct 2011 - July 2012

- Cognitive Science track with concentration in linguistics
- Studied popular science writing

# School of Oriental and African Studies (SOAS, University of London)

Linguistics and Japanese BA

Sept 2007 – June 2011

- First Class with Honors
- Included year abroad in Kyoto, Japan

# Technical Skills

- HTML, CSS, JavaScript, React
- GitHub
- Netlify (static sites, API)
- CMS (WordPress)
- LMS (Moodle)
- Microsoft Office suite including Word, Excel and PowerPoint
- Online collaboration via Microsoft Teams, Dropbox and Google Docs
- Basic familiarity with design tools (Canva, Figma, Adobe Photoshop/ Pixlr, Adobe Illustrator, Final Cut Pro) and audio software (Audacity, Praat)

Robert Grayson